Ankesh Sagar

Senior Marketing Manager – Field & Alliances, AppDynamics India

Summary:

Ankesh is a marketing professional with 9+yrs of experience. He heads India Field & Partner Marketing for **AppDynamics**. He has played a critical role in successfully building awareness and demand globally for Strategic Platforms/Solutions/Products covering Enterprise Integration, Application Modernization, Cloud Integration, Open Source, Legacy Migration, Application Performance Management and Google cloud – AWS. He has defined appropriate messaging, strategizing and implemented comprehensive marketing strategies & integrated campaigns for multiple organizations. Previously he worked with **Wipro, TCS & Infosys** in the areas of Marketing, Project Management, Consumer Finance, Fraud Intelligence and Six Sigma methodology.

Extensive experience in handling key marketing channels - Alliances, Demand Generation, Sales Enablement, Solutions/Product
Marketing, Thought Leadership, Competitive positioning & Intelligence, Media, Events/tradeshows, Influencer-Relationship –
analysts/advisors and Branding (Digital and Traditional Media) – across the customer buying process

Work Experience:

AppDynamics India

Apr 2016 – Present
Senior Marketing Manager – Field & Alliances, Application Intelligence & Application Performance Monitoring

GTM Planning & Execution

- Developing go-to-market strategies for strategic solutions for the business and expanding the market presence of the business through solution marketing initiatives
- Support the revenue and pipeline goals of the India geo aligned to the Sales
- Develop sector business plans around key industry verticals and routes to market
- Able to identify project segment and collect data for customer facing forums

Demand Creation

- · Generate qualified leads and increase customer lifetime value by up selling/cross selling solutions to existing customers
- Plan and develop an accurate and targeted customer and prospect database
- Execute regional events such as webinars, CIO round tables, local 3rd party shows, and end user events with Partners
- Plan, initiate, develop and implement campaigns to develop a sales opportunity pipeline to meet sales targets
- Work with Inside, Channel and Direct Sales teams to create and execute regional Marketing campaigns such as call downs, multi-touch email programs, digital marketing programs, direct marketing for lead generation

Partner Marketing

- Create Joint value proposition and Joint GTM with strategic alliances like Wipro, Infosys, TCS, HCL, Cognizant, NIIT etc
- Working with resellers pan India to generate new business opportunities and successfully converting them to achieve revenue targets

Marketing ROI and budget management

- Measure and report on the effectiveness of all marketing spend against program objectives and manage budget
- Plan, initiate, develop and maintain an effective lead tracking system
- Developing track and report regular ROI figures on the marketing campaigns to ensure continued investment.
- Analyzing ROI on marketing activities, market trends and recommend changes to marketing and business development strategies based on analysis and feedback

Branding & Industry Awareness

- Focus on building awareness through participation in trade bodies and Industry events, analyst and influencer events.
- Managing Local PR activities and deepen relationships with all media to ensure the most effective messaging and positioning of the organization

Wipro Ltd - Dec 2010 – Mar 2016

Senior Marketing Manager, Open Source, Google cloud -AWS & Application Migration/Modernization Platforms

Ankesh has **led** a team of 3. He was responsible to **create Global Marketing & Go-to-market Strategy, coordinate and execute large-scale marketing programs & initiatives**. He worked with Business heads, Technology experts and Strategic partners to envision, develop, launch and sell technology-enabled business solutions. He was part of the core management team and **CEO and CMO reviews**.

Marketing Strategy & Planning

- Develop powerful-high impact marketing campaigns & GTM Strategy to drive adoption through online, offline and partner co-marketing
- Market Segmentation, Opportunity Analysis, Voice of the Customer, Competitive Analysis
- Drive account based marketing, customer adoption, loyalty, account growth and retention
- · Engage in planning and delivery for digital program elements, website, SEO, SEM, Social Media
- Conduct Market Research, understand buying behavior, product composition
- Conduct periodic product/solution analysis and optimize as needed

New Platforms/Solutions/Services Positioning

- Value Proposition Development, Messaging & Pricing
- Create high-impact internal and customer-facing materials that clearly communicate the value & unique advantage of services / solutions
- Develop vertical-specific go-to-market content to better reach target industries and partners
- Field Marketing Programs trade shows, drive promotions, webcasts and direct mail

Lead Generation

- · Responsible for launching demand generation campaigns & finding, generating and qualifying new customers
- Comfortable initiating conversations with the business owners and key decision makers
- Ensures that the potential prospects understand the solution and its benefits
- Capture accurate data about the conversation and maintains detailed communication documentation through internal CRM
- Work closely with the SMEs & sales team to close deals and generate revenues

Partner Relationship

- Develop and manage strategic alliances with leading product vendors like IBM, TIBCO, Oracle, Software AG, Red Hat, WSO2, APIGEE etc.
- Working with resellers across the geo to generate new business opportunities and successfully converting them to achieve revenue targets

Sales Enablement

- Develop and be the custodian of tools and resources to enable sales team, account managers and customer support team to deepen customer relationships
- Help pre-sales / product teams on RFXs responses, designing, sales presentations, sales-kit, demo preparation etc.

Events

- Manage sponsorships and participation at industry, partner conferences and events
- End to end event strategy, planning and execution for international events, booths, conferences, exhibitions
- Generate & track leads in CRM system

Analyst Relations

- Drive analyst engagements and relationships spanning leading analyst firms including Gartner and Forrester
- Develop strategy to positively impact analyst views as well as ensure coverage and positioning as a market leader in schedule reports like Magic Quadrants and Waves
- Manage ongoing communications, updates, briefings, inquiries, customer reference calls and strategy days with analysts to demonstrate market leadership and continually raise awareness

Media Relations

- · Working closely with SBUs and Service lines and strategizing on topics/themes that can be leveraged in media
- Preparing the spokespeople for media interviews
- Editing press releases/articles and advising the businesses around media sensitivities around the messages delivered

Thought Leadership & Marketing Asset Building

- Position Wipro as thought leader by pitching speaker opportunities, whitepapers and point of view articles showcasing
 Wipro and Customer relationship and promote them internally on Website and externally as well
- Digital Marketing Blogs, Social media, Website development and traffic analysis
- Collateral Video, high quality designed brochures, scenarios, story boarding, case studies

Marketing ROI

- Develop, track budgets and measure success of various marketing campaigns
- Drive profitable sales, brand growth and loyalty for a number of solution marketing areas
- Help to achieve product business objectives and revenue goals

Earlier roles played by Ankesh in Wipro

Marketing Manager, Open Source Practice & Strategic Solutions Assistant Marketing Manager, Enterprise Business Integration

Nov 2012 – Nov 2015 Dec 2010 – Oct 2012

Key highlights/achievements:

- Generated revenue of average \$5mn through multiple Market Development events across US & Europe
- Positioned Wipro as Leader in applications space against TCS, Cognizant & Infosys in Analyst's perception
- Industry wide research with 100 CXOs on Open source. Appreciated by "World Economic Forum"
- Created Solution Video which gained 200,000 + hits in couple of months & No. 2 in Wipro Videos on YouTube
- Created "Thought Leadership Journal" which gained traction in customer space with 1000+ downloads
- Started Wipro's Relationship with Penn State University, USA & Cutter Consortium
- Setup the European Chapter of "Integration Advisory Council Customers"
- Y-o-Y increase of 150% in Analyst & Advisor Interactions & 100% in collaterals
- Conceptualized and launched New Services: Integrated Social-Mobility-Analytics-Cloud

<u>Awards</u>

- Golden Bridge Award 2015, USA Best Research of the Year (Global)
- Outstanding Contribution of the Year 2013-14, 2014-15, 2015-16
- Best Marketing Person of the year 2013-14
- Golden Bridge Award 2014, USA Best Online Video of the Year (Global)
- Director's Cut Award 2014 (In-house Film Making)
- Member Wipro's Super Achiever Club 2014
- Feather in the Cap Award, 2012

Work Experience: Infosys Ltd -

June 2009 - Nov 2010

- **Project Lead, Fraud Detection**
 - Managed team of 14 people for Credit, ID and Fraud Assurance for the Global telecom service provider
 - Met SLAs and tracked requirements using day to day operations (quality/TAT/ productivity)
 - Six Sigma Green Belt Project for prevent revenue leakage and increase the customer base. Estimated savings of over
 - GBP 2.5mn due to fraud detection in Roaming, Premium rate, Credit card and Web Sales services

<u>Awards</u>

• Best Team of the year – 2009-10

Work Experience: Tata Consultancy Services Ltd -

Aug 2005 - May 2007

Module Lead, Private Labelled Credit Cards

- Managed a team of 8 people for MCA (Mission Critical Project) of UK based Consumer Finance firm
- Six Sigma Green Belt Project for securing credit card transactions blocked frauds per day saved up to \$10000
- Activity Schedule development, risk identification, impact analysis and quality control

Publications:

- Wipro-Oxford Research (<u>www.wipro.com/microsite/opensource</u>)
- Journal Of Integration (http://www.wipro.com/journalofintegration/)
- Wipro Cutter Consortium Research Report (http://www.wipro.com/microsite/API-report/)

Projects:

- Timken India New product development for Indian auto after market segment after market research in 7 metros
- SBI Business Process analysis, Process discovery, As-Is & To-Be process, Gap Analysis for Personal Loans

Certifications:

- APICS Certified CPIM BSCM Professional (2008)
- Six Sigma Green Belt Certified (2006)

Education:

Program	Institution / University	Year
Executive Programme - Digital Marketing	Indian Institute of Management (IIM), Bangalore	2014
MBA (Marketing)	Symbiosis Centre for Management & HRD (SCMHRD)	2007-09
B. Tech (Mechanical)	S.G.S.I.T.S, Indore	2001-05

Scholastic Achievements:

- Best Marketing Plan for Online gifting portal (SCMHRD Inter School Competition 2009)
- Awarded in Top 5 Summer Internship Projects in Marketing (SCMHRD)

Recommendations:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ankeshsagar